

A.V.V.S. NARESH KUMAR

- +91-8225982485
- <u>naresh.akondi@gmail.com</u>
- linkedin.com/in/a-v-v-s-nareshkumar

CAREER OBJECTIVE & SUMMARY

Result-oriented Professional with 19.6 years of experience in Electrical Packages in Mega Power Plant Projects with extensive exposure in Green field & Brown field projects from concept to commissioning, Operation and Maintenance stage targeting Senior-level assignments in Project Management, Monitoring and Control Functions

Skilled in Project Engineering & Management Using PMP and Six Sigma techniques, deliberate experience in Project Quality, QA/QC, Inspections, Techno commercial, Proposals, RFP, RFQ, Electrical Design Review, Detail Engineering of large scale projects

Experience in driving successful completion of multiple projects and Techno-commercial functions and milestones within time, cost and scope constraints using PMP and Six Sigma techniques, MSP and Primavera tools

Expertise in managing projects and operations with competent cross-functional skills in executing multi-disciplinary activities as well as ensuring on-time deliverables in coordination with internal & external stakeholders

Impeccable record of implementing continuous improvement programs and collaborating with multiple global stakeholders including client, vendors & subcontractors for successful completion of projects

Excellence in developing new proposals, New / Alternative vendors, adopting new technologies, contract management including negotiating the terms & conditions in contracts and ensuring compliance with the same

Skilled in ensuring adherence to Quality and EHS standards like ISO 9002 and ISO 14000, implementing stringent SOP, SMP, quality systems as per IMS, Lean Six Sigma methods to reduce rejection and wastage, Certified Internal Auditor by BV

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY:

TOTAL PROJECTS EXP. In Project Engineering & Management of Electrical Packages (Renewable + Non Renewable)	14.0 Years
TOTAL O&M EXPERIENCE	5.6 Years



SENIOR MANAGER - Project Engineering, QA/QC, Inspections GREENKO ENERGY PVT. LTD. GROUP, Hyderabad / Kurnool

AP01 IREP Project 6x240MW + 2x 120MW PSP & 1600MW Solar & 500MW Wind Project - JULY 2024 - TILL DATE (1.3 Years)



MANAGER, HOD - ELECTRICAL, Project Engineering & Operations KSK ENERGY VENTURES LTD. GROUP, Hyderabad / Bilaspur OCT 2020 - JUN 2024 (3 Years 7 Months)

PLANT#2 - SAI REGENCY POWER CORPORATION PVT.LTD., JAN 2023 – JUN 2024 PLANT#1 - SAI LILAGAR POWER GENERATION LTD., OCT 2020 - DEC 2022

DY. MANAGER (M1), Project Engineering, QA / QC



CG POWER AND INDUSTRIAL SOLUTIONS LTD (Formerly CROMPTON GREAVES), Bhopal

Power Converters & Inverters Manufacturing Unit AUG 2018- SEP 2020 (2 YEARS 2 MONTHS)



TEAM MEMBER -GENERATOR QA & EPS INSPECTIONS SPECIALIST Andritz Hydro Pvt Ltd, (Austrian Based MNC), Bhopal ENGINEERED SUCCESS MAR 2017- JUL 2018 (1 YEAR 5 MONTHS)

> ASSISTANT MANAGER / SENIOR ENGINEER / ENGINEER -Project Engineering & Operations



KSK ENERGY VENTURES LTD. GROUP, Hyderabad / Bilaspur

MAR 2008 - MAR 2017 (9.0 Years)

PLANT#2 KSK MAHANADI POWER COMPANY LTD., JUL 2011 - MAR 2017 6 x 600MW Thermal Power Plant, Bilaspur, CG

PLANT#1 ARASMETA CAPTIVE POWER COMPANY PVT. LTD (Now SAI LILAGAR POWER GENERATION LTD.), MAR 2008 – JUN 2011 2 x 43MW Thermal Power Plant, Bilaspur, CG



TRAINEE / JR. ENGINEER - Project Engineering & Operations REGENCY CERAMICS LTD, Yanam, AP, India

MAY 2006- FEB 2008 (1 YEAR 10 MONTHS)

KEY SKILLS:

Electrical Engineering || Techno Commercial || Quality Management || Proposals & Contract Management || RFP | RFQ | Design Review | Designing of SLDs & Layouts || Equipment sizing & selection || Project Management using PMP and Six sigma || Continuous Improvement || Inspections || IMS Audits || Vendor Management || Operation & Maintenance || Asset Management

SPECIALITIES:

Industry Exposure

- Thermal Power: Ultra-Mega Green Field Thermal Power Project & Operation of 6x600MW BTG & BOP packages, 135MW TPP and 2x43MW captive power plant
- Renewable / Hydro, Solar & Wind Power: Working in India's First Integrated Renewable Energy Project AP01 IREP 1680MW HYDRO Pumped Storage Plant (Generator - Pumps 6 x 240MW +2 x 120MW), 1600MW Solar and 500MW wind in one compound
- Generator Manufacturing up to 240MW & EPC companies
- Manufacturing of Propulsion system, Traction power converters & Inverters, Power Electronics
- 400kV GIS / AIS, 220kV and 132kV AIS Switching stations
- Grev Hydrogen Generation Plant
- Battery Energy Storage System BESS of 11.6MW Solar plant

Project Engineering (Design Review & Technocommercial, Proposals, RFP, RFQ, Inspections)

- Pre Engineering, Technical Proposals & contract writing, RFP, RFQ,
- Detail Engineering, Preparation and review of Layouts, SLDs, Control Schemes Using Auto cad 2012
- Design Review & Approval of SLDs, Layout Drawings, Cable schedules
- Equipment Sizing and Selection, Electrical Specifications
- Protection, Relay coordination, Control schemes and Interlocks
- Collaboration with Customers, consultants, Vendors
- Involved in Project Kickoff & Review meetings

Quality Management, QA/QC of Electrical Power System

- Preparation of Quality Plans (QAPs, FQPs, ITPs)
- Power System Inspections & Supplier Quality
- Internal & External Audits, IMS / Six sigma
- Incoming & In process Quality Control
- QA / Testing, FATs as per IEC, IS standards
- Field Quality Monitoring for Electrical Erection, Testing & Commissioning activities
- Hydro Generator Motors & Turbo Generators, QA / Testing
- Preparation of SOPs, SMPs
- FOR / NCR Raising, RCA, CAPA
- RRT & PG Tests of Turbo and Hydro Generators
- Coordinating Customer Inspections

Commissioning, Operation & Maintenance of **Electrical Power System**

- Thermal Power Plants (4x600MW, 135MW, 2x43MW)
- Power Evacuation & Transmission Lines, 400KV / 220KV / 132KV, Collaboration with CEIG, Transmission & Distribution Authorities,
- DCS, RTU Systems, PLCC / Communication System.
- ABT Metering system, Troubleshooting, Trip Analysis, PM, Condition Monitoring and Major Shutdown Maintenance
- Spares procurement and Maintenance and shutdown contracts management

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS:



B.TECH in ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING REGENCY INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, PONDICHERRY UNIVERSITY, YANAM

Graduated in Year 2006, Achieved First Class, 73.4%



INTERMEDIATE, MATHS, PHYSICS, CHEMISTRY (MPC) S.T.P.P. GOVT. JUNIOR COLLEGE, YANAM

Year of completion 2002, Achieved First Class, 74.3%



SSC (10th Standard), Injaram, Near YANAM ZP GOVT. HIGH SCHOOL

Year of completion 2000, Achieved Honors, 80%

RPROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS:



EMBA (Distance Mode) in PROJECT MANAGEMENT & OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT NIM, Bhopal

Completed in Year 2010



Leadership & Team effectiveness from NPTEL _ IIT ROORKEE

JAN 2023 - APR 2023, Achieved 75%,



Lean Six Sigma Black Belt from CGPISL

Elite Silver Medal Certificate



IMS Internal Auditor training and certification by Bureau Veritas

Completed in SEP 2019

JAN2019 - JAN 2020



Power Systems Selection, Design and Automation By L&T, STC, New Delhi

Completed in MAR 2018

Switchyard and Generator Protections, PLCCs, VFDs, Boiler Automation by KSK

Completed in MAR 2008

Achievements in Greenko Group: (APO1 IREP Project, Kurnool)

- ✓ Involved in Project Quality, Techno commercial activities, preparation of RFP and RFQ, Engineering designs Review, Preparation of As built drawings, Vendor Inspections
- ✓ Successfully taken part in completion of 1680MW India's First PSP (6x240MW +2X120MW)
- Successfully completed RRT, Dry and wet commissioning of 8nos. of Synchronous Generator Motor units, Power Transformers, 400kV GIS Power
 Evacuation System, Trial run Operation in compliance to PGCIL Grid codes and Handed over to O&M through proper HOTO process
- Successfully completed back charging of 700MW pinnapuram solar project and working on 500MW Nagaluti Solar project
- ✓ Prepared and Implemented SOPs, SMPs and LOTO process
- ✓ Involved in QA/QC and Inspections of 1680MW PSP,700MW Pinnapuram Solar Project, 400MW Chanakapalli Solar Project, 500MWp Nagalooti Solar Project & 500MW wind project
- ✓ Major EPC Contractor Engagements in Greenko are Andritz Hydro, Toshiba, Waree, Icom, Amararaja, Mega Engineering (Meil)

Achievements in KSK Energy (2nd Term): (SLPGL 2x43MW TPP, SRPCPL_VSLP 1x135MWTPP, 12MW Solar)

- ✓ Managed all restoration activities of Electrical systems for 2 x 43MW SLPGL TPP & 135MW VSLP TPP, O&M of 11.6 MW Solar plants, Major Shutdowns and overhauling preservation of system when plants in shutdown
- ✓ Design and proposal Development for BESS System for 11.6MW Solar Power Plant
- ✓ Major Client, Contractor, Vendor, OEM engagements in SLPGL: CEIG Raipur for Inspections | | CSPTCL, MRT, Communication Dn. Bilaspur for online tele metering, PLCC, RTU | | CSPTCL Construction for PLCC erection and commissioning | CSPDCL Janjgir | OEGI, India, O&M contractor
- ✓ || Siemens for 560KW ID Fan SINAMICS VFD works || Hitachi Hirel for 4 x 30KVA UPS works || ABB for Unit#1 ID Fan ACS550 VFD works || Vishvas Power, Nagpur for 57MVA GT rewinding and commissioning work || Voltech & Power Test Asia for Testing || Elcon Engineers for Relay Coordination || Turbo Engineering for TG overhauling || RBH Solutions & Airtel for RTU communication with SLDC Raipur
- Managed all Techno commercial activities, Design Modifications, Contracts of Electrical department, New proposals, RFP, RFQs, Technical Scope documents for O&M, AMC contracts, Major overhauling contracts, Repair and testing contracts in HOD role (Lead the Asst. Managers, Shift Engineers, Team of technicians)
- ✓ Responsible for Talent Acquisition, Training the Engineers, Maintained the Attrition rate in dept.
- ✓ Managed O&M contractor for operation & Maintenance, ensured all key deliverables by contractor
- Plant Trip Analysis, RCA, CAPA, Troubleshooting, Import / Export power monitoring, validation of DSM reports & Bills
- ✓ Maintaining trip information correspondence with SLDC Raipur, Form G reports and Inspections by CEIG
- ✓ Preparation of Electrical Budget, Procurement of Critical and running Spares, Managing all commercial functions related to Electrical dept.

Achievements in CGPISL: (IGBT based Power Converter & Inverters Projects, Bhopal)

- Managed 400+ vendors for component supply, Conducted Supplier Quality Audits & Internal Audits as per IMS, Six sigma.
- ✓ Major Vendor engagements for IMS Audits in CG: Leoni Cables | Amphenol Connectors | Hydrodyne Pumps | Kiyosh Resistors | PEC Resistors | Arya Transformers

- ✓ Collaborated with customers from Indian Railways like CLW | DLW | RDSO and RITES for Inspections and Proto Type Inspections and Design approvals of Power converters
- Techno commercial, RFP, RFQ and Quality functions of Inverter and converter panels, Propulsion System Projects, Traction Power Electronics of Power & Aux IGBT converters,
 Rectifier and Inverter modules and various propulsion system projects
- ✓ Lead the team of (Sr. Executives & Executives Mechanical & Electrical + Senior Technicians)
- ✓ Reduced the rejection value to 0.1% from 2% for propulsion system projects by implementation of RCA,CAPA, reworks, replacement of components, raising the return PO requests to purchase, 161 Movements in SAP
- ✓ Managed the QA/QC, Testing cell 5S Compliance & six sigma score at 80%
- ✓ Worked on New Vendor and Alternative vendor Development for component supply

Achievements in Andritz Hydro: (Europe Based MNC, Generator & Turbine Manufacturer, EPC)

- ✓ Underwent training on Electrical equipment selection and design at L&T, New Delhi for one month
- Oversee the various supplier inspections from Bhopal office, Involved in Techno commercial activities, proposals development, RFP and RFQ
- ✓ Involved in Generator In process tests, FATs at Bhopal unit and at various sites
- ✓ Involved in RRT of Generator at 2 sites for 2 generators (Sholayar & Pare sites)
- ✓ Inspections at major vendor plants in India for various EPC projects, all power system equipment
- Major Client, Contractor, Vendor, OEM engagements in Andritz: || NEA & Lehmier International Gmbh, for Upper Tamakoshi & Middle Botakoshi projects || Tamil Nadu Electricity Board for Sholayar Project || Karnataka Power Corp. Ltd, for Bhadra Project || SNC lavalinInc for Hulu, Malaysia project || Bureau Veritas || ERDA India, WEG India, Hosur || C&S, Haridwar for IPBD || Transformers & Rectifiers India Ltd, Ahmedabad || Crompton Greaves, Nasik for GTs || Crompton Greaves, Aurangabad, for Switch yard || Crompton Greaves, Malanpur, Gwalior || Amara Raja Power Systems, Tirupati for Battery chargers and Banks || Volt Amp Transformers, Vadodara || Prime Maiden, Naidupet || KEI Industries, Chopanki, BHIWADI || Tricolite, Gurgaon || Fowler & Westrup, Bengaluru || IEC Insulators, Mandideep || MASS-TECH CONTROLS PVT LTD, Jalgaon || RAYCHEM RGP PVT. LTD. || Rukmani Electrical, Howrah for Tower materials || United Insulations & TMC Transformers, Halol || Various International Clients from Vietnam

Achievements at KSK Energy (1st Term): (6x600MW KMPCL Plant, 2x 43MW ACPCPL now SLPGL Plant)

- ✓ Involved in Project Engineering, Techno commercial, RFP, RFQ, Design development and Review, Detail Engineering & QC Inspections for KMPCL 6 x 600MW & 2x43 MW units from Green field stage to commissioning, RRT, PGT and operation stage and performed activities like Preparation & Review of Drawings, Technical Specifications, Detail Engineering meetings with vendors, preparation of QAPs, FQPs, Kickoff meetings with contractors, Involved in Inspections of onshore Electrical material at vendor plants
- ✓ Involved in Preparation and Review of Designs, Switchyard, Power House, Earthing, Lightening protection Layout drawings, SLDs, Control Schemes, witness of Onsite Testing and Commissioning of 600MW Generators, Transformers, BTG, BOP Electrical Systems, 400kV switch yard, Supported Operation & Maintenance of 3 x600MW units, prepared SOPs and SMPs
- ✓ Successfully commissioned ACPCPL (Now SLPGL) 2 x 43MW Thermal Power plant expansion project, 132KV switchyard expansion and worked in operation, Plant Trip Analysis, RCA. CAPA. Troubleshooting etc.
- ✓ Supervising of Turnkey Electrical Contractor works, Preparation of As built drawings, 2 x 43MW TPP, Supported operation & Maintenance
- ✓ Major Sub Contractor, Vendors, OEM engagements in KSK Mahanadi & Arasmeta Projects: SEPCO, China EPC contractor || L&T || IOTEP || Voltech O&M || OEGI O&M || Power mech || BHEL || Bharat Bijlee || Siemens || Avant Garde, Chennai & DCPL Design consultants ||

Corporate Trainings

- √ Team Alignment& Management by CGPISL
- ✓ Art of living by CGPISL

Awards

- ✓ Long Serving Employee Award by KSK Energy Ventures
- ✓ Achievement award by KSK for part of successful RRT of ACPCPL & KMPCL units
- \checkmark Contribution award received for achieving 400Cr Turnover by CGPISL RTTE division in FY 2019-2020

Software& IT Skills

- OS- Windows 11, Language C, C++, JAVA
- SAP MM Module || ERP Software || PRIMAVERA P6 || MS-PROJECT || MS OFFICE 2023 || AUTOCAD 2012 || ETAP 19 || PVSyst

Languages

- English, Hindi Professional working proficiency
- Telugu, Native working proficiency

I hereby declare that the details furnished above are true and correct

A V V S NARESH KUMAR

VKurnool, Andhra Pradesh, India